(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
みんな元気かー！
How is everyone doing?!
我は元気だぞー！
I'm doing great!
体操いくぞー！
Let's do the exercise!
からだ☆ダンダン
作詞：吉田戦車　作曲：小杉保夫
Karada Dandan
Lyrics: Yoshida Sensha / Composition: Kosugi Yasuo
ゴー！
Go!
からだダンダンだん
Karada Dan-Dan-Dan
ゴー！ゴー！
Go! Go!
からだダンダンだん
Karada Dan-Dan-Dan
ゴー！ゴー！
Go! Go!
からだ冒険、出発進行！
Body adventure, full speed ahead!
さあ、海に潜るよー！
Now, let's dive into the sea!
カニさんエビさんカクカクカクカク
Mr. Crab, Mr. Shrimp, kaku-kaku-kaku-kaku
サメさんサバさんカクカクホネホネ
Mr. Shark, Mr. Mackerel, kaku-kaku-bone-bone
もっと潜ってみよう！
Let's dive deeper!
海藻体操、昆布にわかめ
Seaweed exercise, kelp and wakame
クリオネクリクリクリクリッ
Clione kuri-kuri-kuri-kuri
海藻体操、でんでん太鼓
Seaweed exercise, den-den drum
クリオネクリクリクリクリッ
Clione kuri-kuri-kuri-kuri
クリッ！
Kuri!
さあ、海から出ちゃおう！
Now, let's get out of the sea!
上陸！
Landfall!
ドシン！
Thump!
恐竜になるよ！ガオー！
I'm becoming a dinosaur! Roar!
こどもザウルス、ドシンドシン
Kodomo-saurus, thump-thump
こどもマンモス、ズシンズシン
Kodomo-mammoth, boom-boom
座ってお猿さんになるよ！
Sit down and become a monkey!
グーグーパッパッ　類人猿
Goo-goo pa-pa, anthropoid ape
グーグーパッパッ　現代人
Goo-goo pa-pa, modern human
立つよー！
Stand up!
よー！
Yo!
忍者のおさんぽ、そろりそろり
Ninja's walk, stealthily stealthily
いざとなったらアスリート
An athlete when it counts
走るよ！ついてきてね！
Run! Follow me!
自慢のエンジン、ジンジン燃やせ
Show off your engine, burn it up
ジンジンジンジン！
Jin-jin-jin-jin!
自慢のニンジン、どんどん食べて
Show off your carrots, eat them up
パクパクパクパク！
Munch-munch!
止まるよ！ピタッ！
Stop! Freeze!
ビューン！
Whoosh!
ビューンと風が吹いてきたよ
A whoosh of wind has started blowing
ラララスイスイ、風に乗ろう
La-la-la, glide smoothly on the wind
空を仰ごう、宇宙を覗こう
Look up at the sky, peek into space
ドンドン！
Don-don!
進む地球の子供だよ
Children of the advancing Earth!
だぞ！ゴー！
Yes! Go!
からだ ダンダン ゴーゴー！
Body Dan Dan Go Go!
みんなで ダンダン ゴーゴー！
Everyone together Dan Dan Go Go!
からだ冒険だらけ！おー！
Bodies full of adventure! Oh!
ラプラスさんリモコン
Laplus-san Remote Control
ラプラスさんリモコン！
Laplus-san Remote Control!
カラスは不可×
Crows are not allowed.
いきますよー！
Here we go!
わーいパパ！
Yay, Papa!
パパじゃないです。
I'm not your papa.
いやそういう体だから。
No, that's just the setup.
えー...
Eh...
ラプラスさんリモコン、さ！
Laplus-san Remote Control, 'Sa'!
言いましたよね、無駄使いはしないでって。どうして使っちゃったんですか。
I told you not to waste money. Why did you spend it?
財布はママが管理
Wallet managed by Mama
今後の活動資金はどうするんですか！
What are we going to do for future activity funds!?
じゃあパパはお財布持ってないの？
Then Papa doesn't have a wallet?
聞いてます？
Are you listening?
も、パパはちょっと、あれにハマっちゃってるからね。
Well, Papa's gotten a bit... hooked on that.
お金は、ちょっとね...
So the money is, well...
あれってなに、パパ、あれってなに？
What's 'that', Papa? What's 'that'?
子供が知らなくてもいいことが、この世にはたくさんあるんだ。
There are many things in this world that children don't need to know.
ラプラスさんリモコン、し！
Laplus-san Remote Control, 'Shi'!
死を...待つ...のみ...
I only... wait... for death...
死を…待つ…のみ…
なに？本当になに？
What? Seriously, what is this?
いいかい、みこちゃん。
Listen, Miko-chan.
人間を含むこの世に存在するものは、いずれ滅びると僕は思っているんだ。
I believe that everything in this world, including humans, will eventually perish.
というのも...
And that's because...
(早口の解説)
(Rapid explanation)
ってことだけど、分かった？
...and that's why. Do you understand?
うあ、寝てた。
Whoa, I was asleep.
ふざけんな！
Don't mess with me!
ラプラスさんリモコン、す！
Laplus-san Remote Control, 'Su'!
お待たせしました。
Thank you for waiting.
好きな食べ物が子供っぽいってだけで人を判断するな！
Don't judge people just because their favorite food is childish!
何が好きなんですか？
What do you like?
ハンバーグと唐揚げとオムライスとイチゴのショートケーキとコロッケ。
Hamburger steak, fried chicken, omelet rice, strawberry shortcake, and croquettes.
おい、なんだ。笑ったのか。
Hey, what? Did you just laugh?
このアマ、笑ったのか。
You brat, did you laugh at me?
うわぁぁぁ！
Uwaaaa!
貴様ぁぁ！
You...!
ラプラスさんリモコン、せ！
Laplus-san Remote Control, 'Se'!
世界征服。
World domination.
世界征服！
World domination!
よし、よし。
There, there.
世界征服。
World domination.
そのさ、世界征服ってさ、具体的に何やるの？
So, about that 'world domination', what specifically do you do?
今ってどこら辺まで進んでるわけ？
And how far along are you right now?
毎日遊んでるよね。
You're just playing every day, aren't you?
お父さんの仕事って何なの？
What exactly is your job, Father?
黙れ！
Shut up!
パ、パパ！
Pa, Papa!
【せ】世界を壊す破壊神誕生
The birth of a God of Destruction who destroys the world
ラプラス様にも...
To Lady Laplus too...
もう、完！
Wait, it's already over!
そー！
'So'!
「そ」などはこの世に存在しないのだ！
'So' and the like do not exist in this world!
そ、そうなの！？
W-Really!?
完
The End
良い子のみんなも、一緒に歌おー！
You good kids out there, let's sing together!
せーの！
One, two!
ぺこらんだむぶれいん びっくりだわー
Pekorandemu Brain, what a surprise
生きてりゃ毎日大変
Life's tough every day
大問題のあとには 楽しいことあるから
After big problems, there's always something fun
ぺこらんだむぶれいん 叫んじゃえばー
Pekorandemu Brain, just shout it out
事件だ毎日大変
It's an incident, tough every day
大成功のタネだと 笑えないちゃ、うーな、笑え！
It's the seed of great success, if you can't laugh, then laugh!
ぺ、こ、ら、んだむぶれいん
Pe-ko-ra-ndemu Brain
ぺ、こ、ら、出しちゃいたまえ
Pe-ko-ra, let it all out
No No No 罵れ 欲しがれ 悦ぶな
No No No, curse it, want it, don't be happy
No No No 罵れ ランダムだ
No No No, curse it, it's random
No No No 罵れ 欲しがれ 悦ぶな
No No No, curse it, want it, don't be happy
受け取り拒否ねるぞ！
I'll refuse to receive it!
次は、みんなが大好きなこの曲だよ！
Next up is a song everyone loves!
さあ、行ってみよう！
Come on, let's go!
特者生存ワンダラダー!!
Tokusha Seizon Wonder-la!!
ドドッて ちゃんと ちゃんと 完結して
Dodo-ing, properly, properly conclude
ワンダラ 堂々巡り 完
Wonder-la, going in circles, end
行くぞ！ ちゃんと ちゃんと 供述して
Let's go! Properly, properly testify
ワンダラ 抱負言おう ボクが言うんだもん
Wonder-la, let's say our aspirations, because I'm the one saying them
本気にするんだもん
Because I'm taking it seriously
現実超えろ未来へ
Go beyond reality to the future
逆転も 平気 スイッチ照らしちゃ
Reverse it, it's fine, light the switch
ワンダラ 粗末に しちゃって ワンダラ だって
Wonder-la, treating it poorly, Wonder-la because...
楽しもう 面白がれば こっちの勝ちだ おまえ
Let's have fun, if we enjoy it, we win, you!
返事聞かせてくれ
Let me hear your answer
右に左のこっちゃない
It's not here or there
体制見つけちゃって
Found my stance
ぺこらんだむ発射オーライだ！
Pekorandemu launch, all right!
黙々シャンシャンシャン！
Silent chan-chan-chan!
みんな、ついて来れてるかな？
Is everyone keeping up?
大きなお友達も、小さなお友達も、
Big friends and little friends,
次は一緒に手拍子ね！行ってみよう！
next, clap along with me! Let's go!
それじゃ行くよ。
Here we go.
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
ほめのび
Homenobi
この調子で行くよー！
Let's keep going like this!
褒めてほしいな 褒めてほしいな
I want you to praise me, I want you to praise me
褒めてくれたら 二割増しで頑張る
If you praise me, I'll work 20% harder
見ててほしいな 見ててほしいな
I want you to watch me, I want you to watch me
褒めちぎられて 伸びるタイプです
I'm the type that grows from being praised
もう！
Geez!
みんな、手拍子で盛り上げてくれてありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for livening things up with your clapping!
次の曲は、お姉さんがとっても大好きな曲なの。
The next song is one my big sister loves very much.
みんなも、好きになってくれたらとっても嬉しいな。
I'd be very happy if you all like it too.
ヒロインオーディション
Heroine Audition
ちょっと心細くて
A little bit uneasy
熱い視線送った
I sent a passionate gaze
振り向いててね 笑顔合わせて
Turn around, and match my smile
ヒロインオーディション
Heroine Audition
エントリーしたら私
If I enter, I...
選んでくれるかな
Will you choose me?
まだ子供のみんなにはわからないと思うけど、これから大人になるにつれて、辛いことがたくさんあるかもしれない。
I don't think you kids understand yet, but as you grow up, there might be many painful things.
失礼しますが、RIP♡
Excuse me, but RIP♡
だから、ごめん失礼しますが死んでください
So, sorry, excuse me but please die
Kill the pain 殺すの勝手じゃん、死
Kill the pain, it's my choice to kill, die
Jeez, my life so fucking kawaii
可愛いでしょ？死神、脱落 カリオペ
Cute, right? Reaper, dropout, Calliope
Give me the best piece we get it so higher
叫べよ あんた サイコー
Shout it out, you're the best
Stop please stop is what you're making me
勝手にやって地獄で犯罪じゃないから
Do what you want in hell, it's not a crime
Get up off of some miniature, you're so make-you human nature
でも、お前なんとなーく、一緒に楽しも？
But somehow, let's have fun together?
あなたの死の日まで
Until the day you die
みんな、人生について考える前に、この曲を聴いて元気になろー！
Everyone, before you think about life, listen to this song and cheer up!
Say!ファンファーレ!
Say! Fanfare!
せーの！
One, two!
ほら その手をあげて
Look, raise those hands
みんなで...
Everyone...
踊るステップで...
With dancing steps...
旅の途中...
On the way of our journey...
世界を越えよう
Let's cross the world
せーの！
Ready, go!
全方位お仕事も
All directions and work too
止まらない全力進展中
Unstoppable full-speed progress
Fu!
夢を書き換えたら
If we rewrite our dreams
追いかけ続けよう
Let's keep chasing them
共鳴しあうファンファーレ
The fanfares resonating together
Go!
Shiny Smily Story / 作詞：金丸佳史 / 作曲：中野領太
Shiny Smily Story / Lyrics: Yoshifumi Kanamaru / Composer: Ryota Nakano
だからもっと夢追いかけたい
So I want to chase my dreams even more
ワクワク止まらない
The excitement won't stop
想像越えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that exceeds your imagination
期待してみたい
I want to try having expectations
後悔なんてさせられない
I won't let you have any regrets
それぞれ違った鼓動で
With each of our different heartbeats
走り出そう
Let's start running
みんな、ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you!
#らぷらすとおでかけしてみよう！
#Let's go for an outing with La+!
良い子の皆、刮目せよ！
Good children, pay attention!
吾輩のお名前は、ラプラス・ダークネスだよ。
My name is La+ Darknesss.
お姉さん、普段はお出かけとかあんまりしないんだけど
I usually don't go out much,
今日はとっても天気が良いから、お散歩をしていこうか。
but since the weather is so nice today, shall we go for a walk?
桜の時期はちょっと過ぎちゃったし
The cherry blossom season is over,
紫陽花の季節もまだだけど
and it's not quite hydrangea season yet,
お花さんや動物さん、たくさん見つかるといいね。
but I hope we find lots of flowers and animals.
長い！
So long!
階段、長い！
The stairs are so long!
普段お出かけしねえからな。
Since I don't usually go out...
あーもう辛だわ。
Ah, I'm already at my limit.
ちょっと無理かも知れん。
This might be a bit impossible.
注意
Caution
公園の中はとっても広いんだけど
The park is very large,
フラワートレインで楽々移動できちゃうみたい。
but it seems you can move around easily on the Flower Train.
そこまでの坂道頑張ったのに
Even though I worked hard on the slope up to that point,
一瞬で追い抜かされちゃった。
it overtook me in an instant.
しばらく登ってきて
I've been climbing for a while now
もうヘトヘト。
and I'm exhausted.
結構登ったと思うんだけど
I think I've climbed quite a bit,
頂上はまだかな？
but is the summit still further?
あ、結構階段が長いね。
Ah, the stairs are quite long, aren't they?
おお、この時点でめっちゃ高いかも。
Wow, even at this point, it feels really high.
おお、すご！
Oh, wow!
おおー！
Ooooh!
高ーい！
So high!
結構登ってきたんだな、吾輩。
I've climbed quite a way.
ここまで登ってきた疲れが一気に吹き飛ぶくらいすっごい景色！
The scenery is so amazing it blows away all the fatigue from climbing this far!
街並みが手のひらに乗せられそうなくらい小さく見える。
The town looks so small, like you could fit it in the palm of your hand.
うららキュンとしよ
Urara, let's feel a spark
きっと大丈夫
Surely it'll be okay
しゃがんでジャンプだ
Squat down and jump!
心飛び回れ
Let your heart soar!
うらら 作詞・作曲：水野良樹
Urara. Lyrics & Music by Yoshiki Mizuno
うつむいてみたら
When I looked down...
足が見えたよ
I saw my feet!
固い地面を
Onto the hard ground...
思い切り踏み込むぞ
I'll step with all my might!
顔を上げて変顔しよ
Look up and make a funny face!
背伸びもしてあくびもしよ
Stretch and yawn too!
ご機嫌なファンファーレ
A cheerful fanfare!
嬉しいな
I'm so happy!
うららキュンとしよ
Urara, let's feel a spark!
きっとできるよね
We can surely do it, right?
飛び切りになれるぞ
I can become something extraordinary!
シャガ  4〜5月
Shaga  April-May
心大きくなれ
Let your heart grow big!
ハートぶるぶるやなことに負けないさ
My heart's trembling, but I won't lose to bad things!
楽しもう 楽しんだもん勝ち
Let's enjoy, whoever enjoys most wins!
風を抜け
Breeze through the wind!
うらら涙もさ
Urara, even tears...
幸せの種だ
Are seeds of happiness!
全部優しさに
Let's change it all...
変えちゃおう
Into kindness!
うららキュンとしよ
Urara, let's feel a spark!
ずっと大丈夫
It'll be okay forever!
楽しくいけるさ
We can go on happily!
心飛び回れ
Let your heart soar!
つくろう！お絵描き歌！はじまるよ！
Let's make a drawing song! It's starting!
へえー　便利そう　すごそう
Heh, looks useful. Looks cool.
打って壊したー
I hit and broke it!
あれ？壊してないけど
Huh? I didn't break it though.
壊した！　壊してない！
You broke it! I did not!
ほら！子供たち！ちょっと待って！
Hey! Kids! Wait a second!
壊してない！
I didn't break it!
子供たち！集まって！
Kids! Gather 'round!
帰ります！
I'm going home!
かなたちゃん帰ります！
Kanata-chan's going home!
ほら、入って！入って！
Come on, get in here! Get in here!
ほら！ガキども！これ！
Hey! You brats! Look!
押し通ったら夕飯ないよ！
If you push through, you get no dinner!
やだ！
No way!
早く！座りなさい！
Hurry! Sit down!
ラプラスちゃんがペン壊したー！
Laplus-chan broke the pen!
さっき打ち合わせしたでしょ！打ち合わせ！
We had a meeting just now, didn't we? A meeting!
もう一回最初からやるよ！
We're doing it from the start again!
やだ！
No!
黙って！黙って！黙って！
Quiet! Quiet! Quiet!
早く行け、ガキども！
Go quickly, you brats!
はい。わかったわかった。ラプラスちゃんもね。はいはい。
Yes. Alright, alright. Laplus-chan too. Yes, yes.
いい子だね...
Good girl...
準備して。準備して。
Get ready. Get ready.
皆、私が「始まるよー」って言ったら「わー！」だからね！分かった？
Everyone, when I say "It's starting!", you go "Wah!", okay? Understand?
はい！
Yes!
次！「なんで？」じゃないでしょ。
Next! It's not "Why?", right?
さっきも言ったでしょ。いきますよ！
I told you before. Here we go!
はい！
Yes!
つくろう！お絵描き歌！はじまるよ！
Let's make a drawing song! It's starting!
わー！
Wah!
元気だね！
So energetic!
はい！ということで。一人ずつ自己紹介できるかな？
Yes! And so. Can you introduce yourselves one by one?
はい！
Yes!
はい！天音かなたです！
Yes! I'm Amane Kanata!
（泣き声）
(Crying sounds)
泣かないで、泣かないで、かなたちゃん大丈夫、大丈夫。かなたちゃんのターンだから。
Don't cry, don't cry, Kanata-chan, it's okay, it's okay. It's your turn.
あ、えっと…頑張って、あの、握って…いきたいと思いまふ…
Ah, well... I'll do my best to, um, hold on to things...
あ、ぎゅっと握るんだ。はい、今日も頑張ってぎゅっきゅしていこうね。
Ah, you're going to hold on tight. Right, let's work hard and squeeze things today too.
ぎゅっきゅ！
Squeeze, squeeze!
あーい、よろしくー！
Alright, nice to meet you!
俺の名前はラプラス・ダークネスです！
My name is La+ Darknesss!
れあべた！れあべた！
Le-a-be-ta! Le-a-be-ta!
仲良いね。かなたちゃんとラプラスちゃんは仲良いのかな？
You two get along well. I wonder if Kanata-chan and La+ chan are on good terms?
仲良くない！
We're not!
あ、そういうこと言わないの。ほら、みんな映ってるよ、映ってる。
Ah, don't say things like that. Look, everyone's watching you on screen.
俺はフブキちゃんと結婚するのだ！
I'm going to marry Fubuki-chan!
あ、そうなの？なんかちょっと求婚されましたけど。
Oh, is that so? I guess she just proposed to you.
やだ！やだ！
No! No!
じゃあ、フブキちゃん、自己紹介できるかな？
Now, Fubuki-chan, can you introduce yourself?
白上フブキです！結婚はしたくないです！
I'm Shirakami Fubuki! I don't want to get married!
ねえ、じゃあフブキちゃんは誰と結婚したいのかな？
Hey, then who would Fubuki-chan want to marry?
誰ともしたくないということでございます！
I don't want to marry anyone!
ということで、ラプラスちゃんはちょっと振られたということで。
So, it seems La+ chan was just rejected.
あーん！あーん！
Waaaah! Waaaah!
じゃあ、いろはちゃんお願いします。
Now, Iroha-chan, please.
はい！ござるです！こんにちは！
Yes! De-gozaru! Hello!
良い子なので、自己紹介がちゃんとできました！お姉ちゃん偉い？
I'm a good girl, so I could introduce myself properly! Am I great, big sister?
えらーい！一番えらーい！
Great! You're the greatest!
今日も頑張るでござる！ラプラスちゃんには負けません！よろしくお願いしまーす！
I'll do my best today too, de-gozaru! I won't lose to La+ chan! Please take care of me!
対決なのかな？えらい、えらい、えらい！すごいえらーい！
A rivalry? Great, great, great! So great!
みんな元気に挨拶できたねー。えらい、えらい。
Everyone was able to introduce themselves energetically! Good job, good job.
はい、そしてみんな元気？鷹嶺ルイお姉さんだよー！
And, how is everyone doing? It's your big sister, Takane Lui!
はい、キッズ共、早く座ってください。椅子用意してますんで、はい、座って。
Okay kids, please sit down quickly. I've prepared seats, so sit down.
もう押してるよ。押してるからね。座りなさい。
We're already starting. We're already recording, so sit down.
ということで、子供心を忘れていないみんなに、今から絵描き歌で誰が一番子供に近いか勝負してもらうよ！
So, for all of you who haven't lost your childlike heart, we're going to have a drawing song battle to see who is the closest to a child!
わーい！わーい！
Yay! Yay!
みんな子供心忘れてないよね？
You haven't forgotten your childlike heart, right?
もちろんでございます！見ての通りだよ！
Of course! Just as you see!
ちょっと大人っぽい人いたけど大丈夫かな？今、もちろんでございますって言った人。
Wait, someone sounded a bit adult just now, is it okay? The person who just said 'Of course' like that.
いないよー。子供心を忘れていないということで合ってるかな？
There's no one like that. So it's correct that you haven't forgotten your childlike heart?
大丈夫！大丈夫！みんな企画の趣旨わかってる！
It's fine! It's fine! Everyone understands the purpose of the project!
ビジネス子供！ビジネス子供！
Business children! Business children!
じゃあ、みんな、ルールは簡単！
Alright everyone, the rules are simple!
お姉さんがお題を発表するから、一番子供っぽい絵描き歌を即興で作れた人が1ポイントもらえます。
I'll announce a topic, and the person who creates the most childlike drawing song on the spot gets 1 point.
わかったかな？簡単でしょ？
Got it? Simple, right?
みんな準備はいいかな？
Is everyone ready?
はーい！
Yes!
はい、ということで1つ目のお題はこちら！
Alright, the first topic is this!
ぞうさん
Elephant
ぞうさんです！
Mr. Elephant!
みんなぞうさん描けるかな？
Can everyone draw an elephant?
描ける！描ける！描ける！
I can! I can! I can!
じゃあ、絵描き歌をみんなで考えていきましょう。シンキングタイム、スタート！
Then, let's all think of a drawing song together. Thinking time, start!
みんなはぞうさん好きかな？
Do you all like elephants?
公園でぞうさん見つけたよ！
I found an elephant in the park!
え？公園でぞうさん見つけた？遊具かな？
Eh? You found an elephant in the park? Like playground equipment?
そう！お友達がつるつる滑ってた！滑り台だね、それはね。
Yes! My friends were sliding down it! It was a slide then, wasn't it?
ぞうさんだ！ぞうさん！喧嘩しない、喧嘩しない。
It's an elephant! An elephant! Don't fight, don't fight.
ぞうさんだ、みんな描けたかな？
It's an elephant, is everyone done drawing?
みんな、人のだけじゃなくて自分で考えるんだよ。
Everyone, don't just look at other people's, think for yourselves.
ということで、みんな描けたかな？
So, is everyone done drawing?
描けたー！描けた！
Done! Done!
じゃあ、1人ずつ順番に発表してもらいたいと思います。一番、私が自信あるーっていう人！
Then, I'd like you to present one by one. Who is the most confident?
はーい！はーい！はーい！
Me! Me! Me!
じゃあ、ちょっと子供っぽく「はい」って言った人から指していこうかな。先生、はい、はい！
Then, I'll pick from someone who said 'Me' in a childlike way. Teacher, me, me!
あ、先生、美慈（？）ありがとう。じゃあ、かなたちゃん、一番手！
Ah, Teacher, thank you. Okay, Kanata-chan, you're first!
嬉しい、嬉しい、嬉しい！
I'm happy, I'm happy, I'm happy!
じゃあ、かなたちゃんのぞうさんの絵描き歌！
Then, let's hear Kanata-chan's elephant drawing song!
はい！いってみましょう！
Alright! Let's get to it!
やっていきましょう！ミュージックスタート！
Let's do this! Music, start!
ひとつソーセージがあって
There's one sausage,
そこに……
and there...
ミミズ！ミミズ！ミミズ！
Earthworms! Earthworms! Earthworms!
うまれごとならほくろある
if it's a birthday, there's a mole.
お水がきれい
The water is clear.
そそしてソーセージから何か
A-And then from the sausage, something...
チーズの……あのチビソーセージの……
cheese... that tiny sausage's...
草生えてる！
Grass is growing!
食べ物じゃない！
It's not food!
何か出てきて、これはゾウさんの……
Something came out. This is the elephant's...
ゾウさん！ゾウさんが生まれました
Elephant! An elephant was born!
しっぽもあるよ
There's a tail too.
わあ～！ゾウさん！
Wow! An elephant!
かなたん、絵描き歌はやったことあるかな？
Kanata-chan, have you done a drawing song before?
ある！ある！あるんだ！あるんだね！
I have! I have! I really have!
かなた下手！
Kanata, you're terrible!
すごい上手だったよ！
It was very well done!
あれだね、鼻から鼻水が出てるんだね
I see. Snot is coming out of the trunk.
そうだよ！お水が出てるんだよ！
That's right! Water is coming out!
そうなんや。かわいいね
I see. It's cute.
すごい！足どうなってんの？
Amazing! What happened to the legs?
足変なの。足３本あるよ
The legs are weird. There are only three.
あともう一本どこいっちゃったのかな？
Where did the other one go?
怖いよ！
It's scary!
かなたんよりうまくできるよって人いる？
Is there anyone who can do better than Kanata-chan?
はい！はい！はい！
Me! Me! Me!
じゃあ、やりあってたラプラスちゃんの見ていこうかな
Then, let's see La-chan's, since she's so eager.
見ろよ見ろよ！吾輩の！
Look! Look at mine!
ラプラスちゃんのゾウさん、スタート！
La-chan's elephant, start!
エイ！エイ！ブン！エイ！
Hey! Hey! Boom! Hey!
エイ！手拍子！エイ！
Hey! Clap along! Hey!
絶バイバイバイ！
Des-bye-bye-bye!
まる！
Circle!
大きいチョウチョ！うわあ！
A big butterfly! Whoa!
さんかく！まるまる！
Triangle! Circle-circle!
あし、あし、あし、あし！
Leg, leg, leg, leg!
しっぽ！完成！
Tail! Complete!
いいでしょ？見てよ！
Good, right? Look!
怖い！怖い！モンスター！
Scary! Scary! Monster!
絵描き歌で足のところは「あしあしあしあし」って言うのね
So for the legs in a drawing song, you say 'leg leg leg leg'.
斬新だったね、ラプラスちゃん。鼻と目のシワのディテールがポイント
That was novel, La-chan. The detail of the wrinkles on the trunk and eyes is the point.
ディテールとかいう言葉使わないで、子供が泣いてる
Don't use words like 'detail'. Kids are crying.
下手くそさが本物。今のヒップホップなの？
The badness is real. Was that hip-hop?
ヒップホップだよ！ヒップホップ絵描き歌だよ
It's hip-hop! A hip-hop drawing song!
最近の女性には早かったかな。ちょっとね
I guess it was a bit ahead of its time for modern women.
さっきのかなたんのほうがまだ絵描き歌っぽかったかな
I guess Kanata-chan's earlier one was more like a drawing song.
見て見てこれ！「あしあしあしあし」がちょっと……
Look, look at this! The 'leg leg leg leg' is a bit...
びっくりしちゃったけど、鼻のディテールが怖い
It surprised me, but the trunk detail is scary.
押すな！めっちゃ大きい。ディテールが怖い
Don't push! It's so big. The detail is scary.
すごい！お辞儀も入れて！
Amazing! Put in a bow too!
次、私のほうが上手いよって人！
Next, who thinks they're better?
はい！はい！はい！
Me! Me! Me!
じゃあ、元気がいいフブキちゃんいってみようかな
Then, let's go with the energetic Fubuki-chan.
やる！一番上手く描けるよ！見てて！見てて！
I'll do it! I'm the best at drawing! Watch! Watch!
フブキちゃん早かったもんね、できたのもね
Fubuki-chan was fast, finishing it quickly too.
じゃあフブキちゃんのゾウさんの絵描き歌、ミュージックスタート！
Then, Fubuki-chan's elephant drawing song. Music, start!
なーや！やめろよ！角出て！
Nayya! Stop it! The horns are out!
やめて！大山がひとつ
Stop it! One big mountain.
大山がひとつ、お花がふたつ
One big mountain, two flowers.
お鼻がにょろに、にょきにょきにょきにょき
The trunk goes wiggle-wiggle, growing, growing...
おしりからちょろり
From the bottom, a little wiggle.
ごまとふたつと、ちょんちょんちょんちょん……ゾウさん！
Two sesame seeds and dots, dots, dots... Elephant!
わあ～！ゾウさん！一番ゾウさんみたい！
Wow! Elephant! It looks most like an elephant!
一番上手！ゾウさんみたい！上手！
The best! It looks like an elephant! Great!
かわいいでしょ！ゾウさんのバカかわいい
Cute, right! The elephant is super cute.
フブキちゃんのゾウさんはちゃんと耳が二つあるんだね
Fubuki-chan's elephant has two ears properly.
アピールしないで。君たちのターンは終わったよ
Stop appealing. Your turn is over.
ゾウさんだ。上手い、フブキちゃん
It's an elephant. You're good, Fubuki-chan.
ラスト、いろはちゃんやってみる？
Last, Iroha-chan, want to try?
わかりました！上手に描けてございます！
Understood! I will draw it well!
さぁ、描き歌、象さんも描けるよね、いろはちゃんもね。
Now, for the drawing song, you can draw an elephant too, right, Iroha-chan?
はい、もちろん！象さん知ってる。
Yes, of course! I know what an elephant is.
頭撫でられてますけど。忍者も象さん知らんよ。忍者なの？
You're getting your head patted. Even ninjas don't know elephants. Are you a ninja?
吾輩、象さん乗ったことあるから分かるよ！
I've ridden an elephant before, so I know!
吾輩も象さん見たことあるから分かる！
I've seen an elephant before too, so I know!
違うもん、乗ったことあるもん！乗ったことあるもん！
No, I've ridden one! I've ridden one!
はい、じゃあいろはちゃんの象さんの描き歌...
Alright, then Iroha-chan's elephant drawing song...
レッツスタート！
Let's start!
♪ 長いちくわと...
♪ A long chikuwa and...
♪ 4つのちょんちょこりん...
♪ Four little dots...
♪ 上が大きいお餅...
♪ A big rice cake on top...
♪ ぴょんと尻尾が生えたなら...
♪ If a tail pops out with a boing...
♪ 逆向きのかまぼこつけて...
♪ Attach a backwards fish cake...
♪ 丸とちょんちょんちょん、象さん！
♪ A circle and dot dot dot, an elephant!
おー！すごい！
Oh! Amazing!
ほら、象さん！これ、この間公園で見た象さん見て！
Look, an elephant! Look, this is the elephant I saw at the park the other day!
平日見て、この間見て。いや、かまぼこ書かなきゃいけなくなる...主観ですよね。
I saw it on a weekday, just the other day. No, that would mean drawing a fish cake... that's just your subjective view, isn't it.
歌...何？あの、歌が一番なんかぽかったよ。
The song... what? Um, that song was the most like one.
本当に？ぽかったぽかった。
Really? It felt like it, it felt like it.
かまぼこ、かまぼこ、ちょっとかまぼこ...
Fish cake, fish cake, a bit of a fish cake...
描き歌だったから、ふわっとしていいのよ。ふわっとしても。
It was a drawing song, so it's okay for it to be vague. Even if it is.
でしょ、いいでしょ。めちゃめちゃ良い。すごいアピールしてる。
Right? It's good, right? It's really good. She's really appealing.
この中で一番子供心があった人にね、ワンポイントあげたいと思います。
I'd like to give a point to the person who had the most childlike heart among us.
ほら、お揃い！見て見て、正面見て、横向いてるの、象さん。
Look, they match! Look look, looking forward, and looking to the side, the elephant.
公園で見た象さん、これだったでござる。
The elephant I saw in the park was just like this.
えー、じゃあ、戦った象さん、これ...
Eh, well then, the elephant I fought, this...
じゃあ、子供っぽい子供心を残していた人は...
Now, the person who kept their childlike heart...
フブキちゃん！
Fubuki-chan!
やったー！
Yay!
なんかね、子供らしい言葉選びでね、描き歌をしていたなということで。
It's because your choice of words was very childlike while doing the drawing song.
フブキ社長、ちょっと空気がすごい冷めてるけど大丈夫か？
President Fubuki, the atmosphere has cooled down quite a bit, are you okay?
あ、王冠つけたんだ。"WIN"って書いてね。
Oh, you added a crown. And wrote "WIN".
おしゃ。じゃあ、吾輩やめる。やめないで、やめないで。
Nice. Well then, I'm quitting. Don't quit, don't quit.
それじゃあみんな、二つ目のお題はこちら！
Now everyone, the second theme is this!
カラス！
A crow!
カラスです！
It's a crow!
おー、来たね、カラスちゃんが来ました。
Oh, it's here, the crow has arrived.
みんなカラス、このカラス書けるかな？
Can everyone draw this crow?
可愛いカラスちゃん描いてください。
Please draw a cute crow.
ラプラスちゃんはカラス描けるよね、もちろん。だっていつも一緒よ。
Laplus-chan can draw a crow, right? Of course. Because you're always together.
あ、いつも一緒？
Ah, always together?
うん。え、先生、それがラプラス・ダークネスなんじゃない？
Yeah. Wait, teacher, isn't that Laplus Darkness herself?
違うよ！あれがラプちゃんなの？この子が。確かに。
No! Is that Lap-chan? This one. Indeed.
お前ら、鳥だと思ってんじゃねーよ、この野郎！
You guys, don't just think of him as a bird, you bastards!
誰が、これ誰ユーザー？やばい。そうじゃない。
Wait, who's the user? Oh no. That's not it.
じゃあ、行くか、行くよ、みんな大丈夫かな？カラス、これ見本見ながら大丈夫だからね。
Now, let's go, let's go, is everyone ready? It's fine to look at the reference for the crow.
はい、それではシンキングタイム、スタート！
Okay, then thinking time, start!
あのね、いろはちゃんがカラスの真似上手いよ。
You know, Iroha-chan is really good at imitating a crow.
あ、やってくれる？
Oh, will you do it?
任せて！行くよ。
Leave it to me! Here I go.
(カラスの真似：カァ！)嘘でした！嘘でした！ごめんなさい。
(Crow imitation: Caw!) Just kidding! Just kidding! Sorry.
みんな書けたかな？書けた、吾輩繋げてる、ラプラスに。
Is everyone done? Done, I'm connecting it to Laplus.
一番自信があるよって人、手挙げて！
Raise your hand if you're the most confident!
はーい！あ、フブキちゃんはちょっとあんまり...恥ずかしいの？
Me! Ah, Fubuki-chan is a bit... are you embarrassed?
大丈夫、誰が一番やるかな？
It's okay, who will go first?
ごめん、全然聞こえなかった。なんて言った？
Sorry, I couldn't hear you at all. What did you say?
見てほしいにゃん。
I want you to see it, nyan.
はい、じゃあラプラスちゃんから行こうかな。
Okay, then let's start with Laplus-chan.
では、ラプラスちゃんのカラスの...
Now, Laplus-chan's crow...
吹雪ちゃんのえかきうた、スタート！
Fubuki-chan's drawing song, start!
ワーワー ドードー ワー
Wa wa do do wa
エイ！サッとお山を描きましょー
Ei! Let's quickly draw a mountain.
屋根、屋根、反対の屋根
Roof, roof, the opposite roof.
大きいお山と見せかけてディグダ
Make it look like a big mountain, but it's Diglett.
ディグダ！
Diglett!
丸描いてポーン！これでカラスだ！
Draw a circle and boom! Now it's a crow!
ハトだ！カラスだ！
It's a pigeon! It's a crow!
違う！結構カラスだよ。
No! It's quite a crow.
鶏だね、それ。
That's a chicken.
ラプラスが描いてくれたのかな？
Did La-plus draw that?
ちょっと比べてみようか。
Let's compare them.
違う！横向きして！
No! Turn it sideways!
あ、横向きね。ほらほらほら！
Oh, sideways. Look, look, look!
泣いてる！泣いてるよ！
It's crying! It's crying!
いいじゃん、泣いてるよ。かわいい。
It's fine, it's crying. It's cute.
ねー、でもねー、リズム感は良かったでしょう。
But, you know, the sense of rhythm was good, right?
いいでしょう。
It's good, right?
鶏を描いたということで。
So, you drew a chicken.
カラス！
Crow!
ラプラスの鶏よりも上手にカラス描けるよーって人！
Anyone who can draw a crow better than La-plus's chicken!
はーい！
Me!
吹雪ちゃんが急に自信がついてきたので、
Since Fubuki-chan suddenly got confident...
吹雪ちゃんにお願いしようかな。
...I'll ask Fubuki-chan to do it.
さっきと挙げる手の位置が全然違かったね。
The position of her hand when she raised it was completely different from before.
自信持っちゃったもんね。
She's got confidence now.
そこを見たから。
Because I saw that.
手、見ちゃったからね。
Because I saw your hand.
じゃあ、吹雪ちゃん準備はいいかな？
So, Fubuki-chan, are you ready?
はい、行きます。
Yes, here I go.
はい、吹雪ちゃんのカラスのえかきうた、スタート！
Okay, Fubuki-chan's crow drawing song, start!
ニュニュニュ...
Nyu nyu nyu...
トンネル一つ
One tunnel.
棒ともう一つ
A stick and one more.
お山にニョキニョキ
Sprouting on the mountain.
日が三つ
Three days/suns.
おやおや何これ三角
Oh my, what's this triangle?
かまぼこじゃない竹輪
Not fish cake, but a fish cake tube.
竹輪にちょんちょん
Dot-dot on the chikuwa.
バサバサ翼
Flap-flap wings.
お胸にきらり
Sparkling on the chest.
サザンクロス！
Southern Cross!
カラス！おー上手！
Crow! Oh, skillful!
上手！みんなー！
Skillful! Everyone!
最後！できたー！
Last part! Finished!
さすがサザンクロス。ちょっとびっくりしちゃったけど。
As expected of Southern Cross. I was a bit surprised though.
上手だね。
It's good.
比べてみよう。ほら！
Let's compare. Look!
おー、目、目がね。クオリティ高いね。
Oh, the eyes, the eyes are... The quality is high.
かっこいい。
Cool.
吹雪ちゃんのえかきうたかっこよかったね。
Fubuki-chan's drawing song was cool.
サザンクロスがね。
The Southern Cross.
サザンクロス！サザンクロス！
Southern Cross! Southern Cross!
ちょっとハマっちゃってる。
I'm getting a bit into it.
大爆笑しそうだったけれど堪えました。
I almost burst out laughing but held it in.
吹雪ちゃんより子供っぽくできるよって人！
Anyone who can do it more child-like than Fubuki-chan!
はーい！いろはがいける！
Me! Iroha can do it!
風真先行く？
Kazama, you going first?
お任せあれ！
Leave it to me!
忖度がありましたね。
There was some pre-arrangement.
じゃあ、いろはちゃん、いけるかな？
So, Iroha-chan, can you do it?
見てて！
Watch!
見てるよ。
We're watching.
いろはちゃんのカラスのえかきうたまで、3, 2, 1, スタート！
Until Iroha-chan's crow drawing song, 3, 2, 1, start!
デンデンデン...
Den den den...
大きい鏡餅見つけてドンドコドン
Found a big mirror rice cake, boom-boom-boom.
お弁当の中に入ってるやつ
The thing inside the lunch box.
頭に生やして
Grow it on the head.
トランプのダイヤのマークと逆さまのかまぼこが二つ
A diamond mark from a playing card and two upside-down fish cakes.
お目目を描いて
Draw the eyes.
二つのお羽がバサバサバサ
Two feathers flap-flap-flap.
真ん中に大きな手裏剣描いたら完成
Draw a big shuriken in the middle and it's done.
カラス！ほらできた！
Crow! Look, finished!
ごめんいろはちゃん、すごい後ろの子が...
Sorry Iroha-chan, the girls behind you...
めちゃくちゃ踊ってて、もう歌が頭に入ってこなかったんだけど。
...were dancing so much that the song didn't register in my head.
手裏剣刺してるけど忍者じゃない！
It has a shuriken stuck in it but it's not a ninja!
ダンスのクオリティがすごい高いバックダンサーがいたんだよ。
There were back dancers with really high dance quality.
バックダンサーがいらっしゃいましたよ。
Back dancers appeared.
踊ってくれたの。ラプラスちゃん踊ってくれたの。
They danced for me. La-plus-chan danced for me.
あらた！
Alata!
はい、ありがとう！
Yes, thank you!
あ！
Ah!
ラプラス、やるよ。
La+, I'll do it.
うわ、ね。
Whoa, right.
あのお腹の部分、なんか、かなたちゃんのね、あの手裏剣みたいに見えてきたんだけど。
That stomach part started looking like Kanata-chan's shuriken.
手裏剣？
Shuriken?
頭に付いてる！
It's on her head!
ヘリコプターだ！
It's a helicopter!
よし、じゃあ、かなたちゃん！
Alright then, Kanata-chan!
準備はいいかな？
Are you ready?
いいよ！
I'm ready!
はい、かなたちゃんの、カラス絵描き歌、行ってみましょう！
Alright, let's go with Kanata-chan's Crow Drawing Song!
どうぞ！
Go ahead!
メンタコ、メンタコ、海だ、海だ。
Mentako, Mentako, it's the sea, the sea.
わなにかかってるね。
It's caught in a trap, isn't it?
グシグシ。
Gushi gushi.
となりにドンブリ、となりにドンブリ。
A bowl next to it, a bowl next to it.
仲良く吉野家、仲良く吉野家。
Friendly at Yoshinoya, friendly at Yoshinoya.
わからない。
I don't know.
ちょっと可愛い感じに、ちっちゃなお耳ができた。
To make it a bit cute, small ears are made.
ここで変わっちゃうよ。
It's going to change here.
ビヤラム付けたらできる。
If you add Biyaramu, it's done.
ここのサンゴ、海のサンゴ。
The coral here, the coral of the sea.
キラキラキラ、できたよチョコボ！
Sparkle, sparkle, sparkle, a Chocobo is done!
チョコボだね、それはね！カラスじゃないね！
That's a Chocobo, isn't it! It's not a crow!
できた！チョコボだ！
Done! It's a Chocobo!
すごい！チョコボだ！歌が違くなっちゃうね、それね。
Amazing! It's a Chocobo! The song would be different, wouldn't it?
四匹の中では、チョコボが強いみたいだったけど。
Among the four, the Chocobo seemed strong, but...
子供心を残していた人は...ドゥルルルルル...ダン！
The person who kept their child's heart is... (drumroll)... Bam!
いろはちゃん！
Iroha-chan!
やったー！まさかの最弱！
Yay! Unbelievably, the weakest!
じゃあ、全部のお題が終わったのね。
Well then, all the themes are finished.
ベストオブ子供心を決めたいと思います。
I'd like to decide the Best of Child's Heart.
準備できてますか？座って！
Are you ready? Sit down!
はい、ということで、一番子供心があった子は...
Yes, so, the child who had the most child-like heart is...
誰かな、誰かな、誰かな、誰かな...
Who is it, who is it, who is it, who is it...
ラプラスちゃん以外です！
Anyone except La+!
おめでとう、みんな！おかしい、おかしい！
Congratulations, everyone! That's weird, that's weird!
素晴らしい！これはね、ご褒美がありまして。
Wonderful! There's a reward for this.
ルイお姉さんに、目一杯甘やかしてもらって良いことになっております！
You'll be spoiled to the fullest by Lui-oneesan!
この後、じゃあ、私の家でご飯食べようね。
After this, let's eat at my house, okay?
みんなの大好きな、何食べたい？何食べたい？
What do you want to eat? What do you want to eat?
ハンバーグ！ハンバーグだね、ハンバーグ食べようね。
Hamburgers! Hamburgers, right? Let's eat hamburgers.
みんなでハンバーグ食べよう。
Let's all eat hamburgers together.
吾輩も、吾輩もいいですか？
Me too, can I join too?
逆に子供から最も遠かったのは、ラプラスちゃんです！おめでとう！
Conversely, the one furthest from a child was La+! Congratulations!
おめでとう、お疲れ様でした！大人みたいでございます。
Congratulations, good job! You're like an adult.
ラプラスちゃん、本当に今日ね、頑張っていらっしゃいました。
La+-chan, you really worked hard today.
できた！お疲れ様です！そんなあなたにお仕置きがあります！
Done! Good job! There's a punishment for you!
お仕置き？お仕置きの内容は...
Punishment? The content of the punishment is...
ルイお姉さんに踏まれるです！
Being stepped on by Lui-oneesan!
それはいいですよ！ということで...
That's actually good! So...
じゃあ、みんなで踏もうか、みんなでね。
Well then, shall we all step on her together?
いやいや、いいやみんなで、ルイだけでしょ！
No no, it's fine, all together... Only Lui, right!
え、ルイだけでしょ？踏まれるに決まってんじゃん！
Eh, only Lui, right? It's decided I'm being stepped on!
じゃあ一人ずつ、目瞑って待ってて。
Then one by one, close your eyes and wait.
嘘、放置プレイ？目瞑って、じゃあ踏むね。
No way, neglect play? Close your eyes, and I'll step on you.
別に嫌いじゃないですけどね、そういうの。
I don't particularly dislike that kind of thing, though.
じゃあ行きますよ。順番決めてるから、誰からにしようか。
Here we go. We're deciding the order, who should go first?
こういうのも別に嫌いじゃないんで、待ってますよ。
I don't dislike this kind of thing either, so I'm waiting.
じゃあ、みんなお別れの挨拶、せーの、バイバーイ！
Alright, everyone say goodbye. One, two, bye-bye!
嘘でしょ、一番のお仕置きじゃん、それは！
You're kidding, that's the biggest punishment ever!
シャキーン！
Shakiin!
ぱわぷたいそう！
Pawa-Puta-Isou!
パララパワーアップ、パワーワ、パララパワーアップ。
Parara power up, power-wa, parara power up.
パワーパ、パララパワーアップ、パワーワ。
Power-pa, parara power up, power-wa.
お日様がのぼるパワー！
The sun rises, power!
かるきだして
Take a light step
とっぱかじゃんけんぽん
Rock-paper-scissors shoot!
グーだってチョキだって
Whether it's rock or scissors
パはパはパはパ！
Paper is power-power-power-pao!
パ！
Pao!
パワーパワーアップアップ！
Power power up up!
顔洗うよ
Wash your face
顔洗って僕の手のひら
Wash your face and show your palms
お日様に見せて
To the sun
顔パパパ！
Face pa-pa-pa!
歯磨き
Brushing teeth
歯磨き嬉しいパ
Brushing teeth is happy pa
元気だパオ
Energetic pao
ピキピキ楽しいパ
Sparkling fun pa
お日様パオ
Sun pao
行ってきまーす！イエイ！
I'm off! Yay!
ピヨピヨピヨピヨピヨ
Piyo piyo piyo piyo piyo
ピヨピヨピヨピヨピヨ キッキッキ
Piyo piyo piyo piyo piyo ki-ki-ki
小さなパワワ
Small power
大きなパワワ
Big power
ウキウキパワワ
Cheerful power
ぞうさんパワワ
Elephant power
青い空へ高く
Into the blue sky, high
ジャンプだー！
Jump!
パワパワパワパワパワワ
Power-power-power-power-power
ピキピキパワパワパワワ
Sparkling power-power-power
パワパワパワパワパワワ
Power-power-power-power-power
ウキウキパワパワ
Cheerful power-power
パワパワパワパワパワワ
Power-power-power-power-power
楽しいパワワッパ！
Fun power-pa!
グーだってチョキだって
Whether it's rock or scissors
パだってパワパワじゃんけんぽん！
Even paper is power-power-rock-paper-scissors shoot!
誰だ誰だ誰だ誰だ
Who is it, who is it
パワパワパワ
Power-power-power
パワパワパワパワ
Power-power-power-power
大きな声でパワパワ
With a big voice, power-power
パワパワパワパワ
Power-power-power-power
元気な声でパワー
With an energetic voice, power
パワパワパワパワパワワ
Power-power-power-power-power
幸せパワパワパワワッパ！
Happy power-power-pa!
パッ！
Pa!
ホロクス君、こんにちは。
Holox-kun, hello.
今日はね、お姉さんがいいもの見せてあげちゃうよ。
Today, Big Sister is going to show you something good.
お母さんには内緒かもね。
It might be a secret from your mother.
これ見て。
Look at this.
ラプラス・ダークネス誕生日記念グッズって書いてあるね。
It says "La+ Darknesss Birthday Celebration Goods."
知ってるかな？
Do you know about it?
いや、知らなくてもいいんだけどさ、ちょっと見てってよ。
Well, you don't have to know, but take a look.
これアクリルスタンドって言うんだけど、知ってる？
This is called an acrylic stand, do you know?
どう？なんか薄っぺらい板。食べちゃダメだよ。
What do you think? It's like a thin plate. You can't eat it.
ほら、可愛いねイラストが。
See, the illustration is cute.
まだそういう年頃じゃないかな？
Maybe you're not at that age yet?
これとっても可愛いでしょ。
This is very cute, right?
次、これ。ラプラスパペット。
Next is this. La+ Puppet.
ぬいぐるみだね。でも普通のぬいぐるみじゃないんだよ、これ。
It's a plushie. But it's not a normal plushie.
パチパチってこうして...こうして手にはめるとね、喋らせられるんだ。
You go "snap-snap" like this... and when you put it on your hand, you can make it talk.
ラプラス・ダークネスに好きなこと言わせられるってね。
You can make La+ Darknesss say whatever you want.
変な使い方しちゃダメだよ。お母さんに言っといてね。
Don't use it in weird ways. Tell your mother, okay?
お兄ちゃんにも言っといて。
Tell your older brother too.
最後、これ。おしゃぶり型スマホリング。
Lastly, this. Pacifier-shaped smartphone ring.
スマホ持ってるかな、ホロクス君。
Do you have a smartphone, Holox-kun?
ええー！その年で持ってるの？
Whaaat! You have one at that age?
変な使い方しちゃダメだよ。
Don't use it in weird ways.
ね、これ全部。これ全部入れたフルセットっていうのがあってね。
See, all of these. There's a "Full Set" that includes everything.
これを購入してくれた人にはですね、特典が2つ付いてきちゃうらしい、2つ。
For those who purchase this, it seems there are two special bonuses, two.
特典ってわかるかな？難しい言葉使っちゃったね。
Do you know what "bonus" means? I used a difficult word.
なんかね、おまけ、おまけだよ。ラムネのお菓子みたいに。そうそう、あんな感じのやつね。
It's like an extra, a freebie. Like the candy in Ramune. Yeah, that kind of thing.
1つ目は、ラプラス・ダークネス箔押し複製サイン入り、絵師さんの描き下ろしチェキ風ブロマイド。
First is the La+ Darknesss foil-stamped reproduced signed, artist-drawn cheki-style bromide.
長いね、特典の名前が。わかったかな？
The bonus name is long. Did you get it?
ま、このラプラス・ダークネスさんのね、複製サインっていう、なんか一杯、一杯のサインがね、入ったブロマイドがもらえるわけですね。
Well, you get a bromide with a reproduced signature of La+ Darknesss, like, lots and lots of signatures.
いらない？
You don't want it?
あんなこと言わないでよ、ちょっと。欲し...欲しがるよ、それは。
Don't say that. You'll... you'll want it.
お母さんに言っといて。「欲しい！」って。
Tell your mother. Say "I want it!"
いらなくても、「欲しい！」って。買ってもらって。
Even if you don't need it, say "I want it!" and have her buy it.
で、あと2つ目。特典...
And then the second bonus...
ボイス、『ラプラスといっしょ』。
The voice pack 'Together with Laplus'.
ね、これちょっと...
Hey, this is a bit...
ちょっとね、いかがわしいんじゃない、いかがわしいボイスなんじゃないって思うよね？
You might think it's a bit suspicious, like a 'suspicious' voice pack, right?
全然違います。全然普通のボイスなんでね。
Not at all. It's just a totally normal voice pack.
ちょっと詳しい内容は言えないんですけど、
I can't really tell you the details, but...
まあちょっとね、貴公、君がね、いい感じにラプラスさんとね、
Well, you see, you'll be able to, um, interact with Laplus-san in a nice way,
関われちゃう、関われちゃう、関われちゃうんじゃないの？っていうボイスですね。
...interact, interact, interact with her, you know? That's what kind of voice pack it is.
聞きたい？ 聞きたいよね？
Want to hear it? You want to hear it, right?
そう、買って。買って。
Yeah, so buy it. Buy it.
はい、分かったかな？
Okay, did you get it?
はい、以上、商品紹介でした。
Okay, that's all for the product introduction.
最後は、『あしたてんきになーれ』！
Lastly, 'May Tomorrow Be Sunny'!
世界はとっても広いから
The world is very wide,
夢も大きい方がいい
So it's better to have big dreams too
夢に向かって発進！ オーライ！
Heading towards our dreams! All right!
さあ、元気に行くよ！
Now, let's go energetically!
晴れ、晴れ、晴れ
Sunny, sunny, sunny
きっと晴れる、明日も会える。また遊ぼうね！
It'll surely be sunny, we can meet tomorrow too. Let's play again!
晴れ、晴れ、晴れ
Sunny, sunny, sunny
きっと晴れる、明日も会える。
It'll surely be sunny, we can meet tomorrow too.
そろそろおしまい！
It's almost over!
トンネルの向こうは、青空がいっぱい
Beyond the tunnel is full of blue sky
両手を広げて、世界が待っている
Spread your arms wide, the world is waiting
じゃあみんな、バイバイ！ まったねー！
Well then everyone, bye-bye! See ya later!